AASHISH MANDYAANILKUMAR

Dallas, Texas | aashish.jain.ma.94@gmail.com | (469) 380- 4580 | LinkedIn | Github

DATA SCIENTIST, M.S Data Science

Proactive problem solver with excellent communication abilities and Master's degree in Data Science. Seeking the position of Data Scientist to apply in-depth understanding of advanced statistical and predictive modeling concepts Bringing 3 years data science work experience with solid programming skills.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: R, Python, SAS, Oracle SQL, MS SQL Server, MySQL

Tools: Advanced Excel (V-Lookup, pivot tables, macros), Tableau, PowerBI, Google Analytics, AWS S3, AWS Redshift

Packages: dplyr, ggplot2, caret, tidyverse, reshape, R Shiny, Pandas, NumPy, matplotlib, seaborn, sklearn Statistical Skills: Hypothesis testing, t-test, f-test, ANOVA, A/B testing, Linear Regression, Logistic Regression, Clustering, Forecasting (ARIMA), SVM, PCA, CART, KNN classifier, Naïve bayes, Random forest, Decision trees

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

American Home Shield (Frontdoor), Memphis

June 2019 - Present

Data Science Intern (Marketing, pricing & strategy)

- Designed & developed predictive models & learning algorithms to calculate customer retention for 2M users
- Formulated new forecasting models for claims & severity to calculate *Customer life-time value* which helped the business to segment customers in to high, medium and low priority
- Achieved **8% increase** in conversion rate by creating customer profiles using various classification techniques which helped the marketing team for effective targeting of ads
- Created Visualisation dashboards to effectively track KPI's for the purpose of supporting operations & maintenance departments which was used by company leadership

Technologies & Skills: R, Python, SQL, Power BI, Logistic regression, ARIMA, Poisson regression, Survival analysis

Lymbyc Solutions, Bangalore

January 2017 - July 2018

Business Data Analyst

- Programmed an interactive route optimization tool using multiple traveling salesmen algorithms on RStudio & earned Lymbyc Spark Award
- Analyzed & identified process time deviations leading to improved SLA of the supply chain by over 25%
- Built & automated Excel dashboards to analyze quarterly sales & revenue generation opportunities
- Defined crucial metrics & assessed Mobile App traffic across various states for national e-learning platform

Technologies & Skills: R, Python, Data Mining, Data Wrangling, Statistical Analysis, Machine learning, Clustering

Shadowfax Technologies, Bangalore Data Analyst (Supply chain & strategy)

September 2016 - December 2016

- Extracted, integrated and analyzed real time data using MySQL, made quantitative analysis using this data
- Collaborated with supply team to devise an incentive plan for drivers hence reducing driver cancellations by 15%

EDUCATION

The University of Texas at Dallas

Dallas, TX

Fall 2018 - May 2020

Master of Science, Data Science

GPA: 3.7

BMS College of Engineering Bangalore, India

Fall 2012 - May 2016

· Bachelor of Engineering, Industrial Engineering and Management

GPA: 3.5

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

KPI Dashboard Creation Using RShiny App

September 2018 - Present

• Defined crucial metrics & designed multiple RShiny Apps for Interactive visualizations: Movies, Accidents, Books

Prediction of House Sales prices

January 2019- Present

Predict house prices for home buyers and sellers using advanced regression techniques: Python notebook
 Skills: SVR(linear & kernels), Lasso, Ridge, Bagging, Boosting, Pasting, Deep Learning, Neural Net, Data Structures
 Data warehousing using AWS
 August 2019 - December 2019

Created MySQL DB instance using Amazon RDS, Deployed a data warehouse using Amazon redshift

Skills: Amazon RDS, Amazon S3, Amazon Redshift, Amazon EC2, Amazon Kinesis, MySQL, Big data

Prediction of Customer Rating for E-commerce retail

September 2018 - December 2018

• Predict customer rating to understand factors affecting order fulfillment for an E-commerce organization: Kaggle